<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Vatsal&#39;s Terminal</title>
    <link>https://vatsalmpatel.github.io/vatsalportfolio/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Vatsal&#39;s Terminal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Vatsal Patel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vatsalmpatel.github.io/vatsalportfolio/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello Friend</title>
      <link>https://vatsalmpatel.github.io/vatsalportfolio/posts/greet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatsalmpatel.github.io/vatsalportfolio/posts/greet/</guid>
      <description>As you have come to my website, this is a chance for you read more about me as well as take a look at various Machine Learning and Deep Learning Projects that I have worked by navigating the links above and feel free to contact me and we can have a chat 🗣.
A short intro I am currently a full-time student at Northeastern University, pursuing my Masters in Artificial Intelligence, inclined towards Machine Learning and Computer Vision.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;As you have come to my website, this is a chance for you read more about me as well as take a look at various Machine Learning and Deep Learning Projects that I have worked by navigating the links above and feel free to contact me and we can have a chat 🗣.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-short-intro&#34;&gt;A short intro&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently a full-time student at Northeastern University, pursuing my Masters in Artificial Intelligence, inclined towards Machine Learning and Computer Vision. I love to work on deep image models, constantly trying out new models followed by their training and testing on images to gain useful insights on the data and work on it to make it better. I recently started to learn more about self-driving cars and the technology behind them and the state-of-the-art models used to govern self-driving cars. I also love learning about Machine Learning algorithms and gathering insights on how they were used to solve problems that changed the landscape of AI. Recent applications of AI in self-driving technology and seeing the ability of those models to predict/output useful constructs from the features they learn excites me and it is what motivates me to keep exploring more and learn about AI.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
